Guide to the Office of Sponsored Research records, 1942-1996 RG0038
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Project files for programs and institutes, 1950-1982; RG0038 Series 5; 10 Linear feet
  - Special Education: Moss, Margaret H Final Report, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Project TOBI: The Development of a Pre-School Achievement Test
  - Special Education: Progress Report 2, 10/15/1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Special Project Grant: Complementary Teacher Training Program Academic Year 1972-1973
  - Special Education: Final Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Diagnostic/Prescriptive Teacher Project Department of Special Education, School of Education
  - Special Education: Non-Categorical programs in Special Education, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Proposal submitted to the Bureau of Education for the Handicapped for a 3 year cycle, volumes I, II, and appendices
  - Logistics Research: Project Bibliographies, 1956-1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Logistics Research: Project Bibliographies, 1956-1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Logistics Research: Notes on the Cuban Crisis of April 1961, 07/12/1961 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Logistics Research: Logistics Papers, 02/1950 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Quarterly Progress Report 1
  - Logistics Research: Minutes of the 3rd Annual Logistics Conference, 01/1952 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Logistics Research: GWU Logistics Papers, 02/16/1954 --05/15/1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Logistics Research Project, 07/1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - School of Engineering and Applied Science: Accomplishments, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - School of Engineering and Applied Science: Semiannual Status Reports, 1976-1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    #20-32
  - Medical Center Populations Reports: Population Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    newsletters
  - Medical Center Populations Reports: Cumulative lists of Population Reports, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Medical Center Populations Reports: The Population Information Program, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Medical Center Populations Reports: GWU Sesquicentennial, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Medical Center Populations Reports: Population Reports, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    binder
  - Naval Research: Econometric Research, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Naval Research: Defendant-Related Benefits and Reenlistment, 06/1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1968 --09/30/1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Semiannual status report 5
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 10/01/1968 --03/31/1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Semiannual status report 6
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1969 --09/20/1969 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Semiannual status report 7 (2 copies)
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 10/01/1969 --03/31/1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Semiannual status report 8
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1970 --09/30/1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Semiannual status report 9
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 10/01/1970 --03/31/1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Semiannual status report 10
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1971 --09/30/1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Semiannual status report 11
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 10/01/1971 --03/31/1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Semiannual status report 12
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1972 --09/30/1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Semiannual status report 13
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 10/01/1972 --03/31/1973 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Semiannual status report 14
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1973 --09/30/1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Semiannual status report 15
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 10/01/1973 --03/31/1974 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Semiannual status report 16
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1974 --09/30/1974 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Semiannual status report 17
  - Naval Research: Program in logistics, 04/01/1975 --09/30/1975 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Semiannual status report 19
  - ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education: Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education: Quarterly Progress Report, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education: Publications, 1965-1977 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Combined Annual Report and continued renewal proposal: Lipid Research Clinic at GWU Medical Center, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    2 copies in binder
  - Problem oriented record through life skills: Final report, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Geneva S Folsom, Principal investigator
  - Problem oriented record through life skills: Manual for training clients, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Level IV and V by Shirley Zamna
  - Problem oriented record through life skills: Manual for training clients, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Level II beginning and advanced, and Level III by Jean Federici
  - Medical Center: Annual report, 03/1980 --02/08/1981 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Medical Center: Final report of the health systems and resource allocation model, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Volume I in binder
  - Medical Center: Final report of the health systems and resource allocation model, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Volume II in binder
- Lists of sponsored research awards, 1980-1988; RG0038 Series 6; 1 Linear foot (Box 1)
  This series consists of lists of sponsored research awards. They are arranged chronologically. The materials range in date from 1980-88, and were added to the University Archives collections from a backlog in 2000.
- Alleghany ballistic laboratory project files, 1942-1967; RG0038 Series 7; 2 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2)
  This series consists of files from the Allegany Ballistics Laboratory, which researched and developed missiles for the U.S. government during World War II. Materials include memos, correspondence, flight test reports, drawings, blueprints, and part of a missile housing. It also includes files from the Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO). They are arranged alphabetically by subject files. The materials range in date from 1942-47, and were transferred to University Archives by the Director of Sponsored Research in 2000.
  - Allegany missile project - memos, correspondence, drawing of assembly, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allegany missile project - memos, correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - File W-8 final report, sections IV and V - Tests and report, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Flight tests of H4.5 rockets (1944); Ground penetration tests of 115mm T87 rockets fired from aircraft (1945); Final report of the dispersion tests conducted at Elgin Field, FL on rocket 4.5 in., practice, T87" (1945)
  - File W-8 final report, sections III and IV - Tests, memo and notes, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Screwed and welded scrap tests for 60 and 100 lb. H-4.5 in. rockets (1944); Supplement to memorandum of May 15 on screwed and welded trap tests for the 60 and 100 lb. H-4.5 in. rockets (1944); Static firing test of mid-spacer modified 100 lb. Rocket trap (1944); Notes on recent trap failures of H-4.5 in. rockets (1944); The development of a theory of the internal ballistics for the Budd 4.5 or similarly constructed motors (1943); Current status of propellant charge for H-4.5 rocket (1944); Temperature performance of H-4 and RS-1 powders - static firings in H-4.5 rocket (1944); Flight tests of H-4.5 rockets (1944)
  - File W-8.1 final report, sections VII and VIII - Tests and reports, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    115 mm aircraft rocket flight test, performance of C-7 trap with 20 in. H4 powder grains (1944); Interim report of static tests of drilling patterns for the 115mm rocket [twelve grain charge] to 5/3/45 (1945); Test report. High temperature performance of 115 mm aircraft rocket with production trap [D2010cl] and 20.6 inch T2 powder grains with simple drilling patterns (1945); Flight tests of propellant charge and trap [2010C-1] in 115mm rocket [production model] at-40 degree and-60 degree F (1945); Comparison of powders RPL 458, 660, and 672 in the 115mm rocket (1945); Test report - 115mm aircraft rocket (1945); Proof tests of 75g igniter with the NH9 Squib (1945)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section IV - Summary and tests, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Summary of recent H-4.5 tests (1944); Flight tests of H-4.5 rockets (1944); Jet malalignment of the H-4.5 inch (1944); Wave length of yaw of the heavy H-4.5 in. rocket (1944); Aerodynamic characteristics of the half scale NDRC model 3.25 inch signal rocket (1944); Wind tunnel data, H-4.5 in. rocket (1944); Plane firings of H-4.5 on Oct. 4 and 6 at Bombay Hook Range, Dover, DE (1944); Aircraft firing at Dover, DE (1944); Test to determine combination of pilot error, launcher error, and ammunition error in plane to ground firing of T83 - H-4.5 in. rocket (1944); Aircraft firing at Dover, DE (1944); Ammunition dispersion test of 115mm T78 rockets fired in pairs from P47 airplanes at speed at 300 mph, 0 degree dive, range 500 yd (c.1944)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section VI - Summary and tests, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Summary of progress on the H-4.5 in. rocket (1944); Attempted blow up of hydril-kobe chamber #50 (1944); Distortion of H-4.5 chambers in heat treatment (1944); Heat treatment of H-4.5 chambers (1944); Comparative dispersion tests of heat treated hydril chambers and unheat-treated kobe 115mm motors (1945); Chamber tests of hydril heat treated and kobe unheat-treated motors (1945); Brazing test for H4.5 rocket for Allegany Ballistic Laboratory (1944)
  - File W-8.2 final report, sections VII and VIII - Memos and letters, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Memo from Gibson to Hardy, 11/6/44; Memo by Shryock, 12/23/44; Letter from Engstrom to Rosenberg, 11/27/44; Letter from Mumma to Glen, 11/20/44; Progress on malalignment measurements memo, 1/10/45; Components of malalignment in 115mm rockets memo, 5/31/45; Gas malalignment in 115mm rockets memo, 6/21/45; Optical malalignment of production model 115 mm rockets memo, 4/3/45; Ordnance production rounds for Dover tests memo, 8/1/45; Ammunition dispersion of the production model of 115mm rockets memo, 5/26/45
  - File W-8.2 final report, section III - chamber and head designs for H-4.5 rocket, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section IV - drawings and memos not used in report bibliography, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section V - Hydril Corporation memos, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section VI - heat treatment memos and data not used in report bibliography, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section VI - chamber strength memos and data not used in report bibliography, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section VII - various tests and diagrams not used in report bibliography, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - File W-8.2 final report, section VIII - malalignment data not used in report bibliography, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Rocket Ordnance: Development and Use in World War II - booklet, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Organizational chart for Research Division of Allegany Ballistics Laboratory, 08/1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Program of Events at Allegany Ballistics Laboratory, 11/08/1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - File W-82.02 - Tentative drawings of H-4.5 inch (115mm) aircraft rocket, 11/03/1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - File W-82.08 - Proof tests of 115 mm rocket; memos, data, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - File W-81.08 - Proof tests of 115 mm rocket; memos, data, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - File W-82.09 - Notes on joint Army-Navy conference on rockets, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - File W-82.04 - Planning and conferences memos on 115 mm rocket, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - File W-81.05 - Supply and shipment of rockets, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - File W-81.05 - Supply and shipment of rockets, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - File W-80.05 - Supply and shipment of rockets, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - File W-81.05 - Supply and shipment of rockets, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - File W-82.05 - Disposition and status of shipment of rockets, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - File W-84 - 115mm rocket with MJA powder, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - File W-84.10 - Propellant charge, data and memos, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - File W-8.3 - Development of heads and fuzes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Classification of CWS projects, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Condensed project status surveys, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Project committee meetings minutes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Post war propellant research, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Fuzes (T1E2), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Fuzes (Mk149), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - File W-80.3 - Heads and fuze tests, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - File W-82.30 - Tests for heads for 115mm rocket, including photographs, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - File W-82.40 - Fuze tests for 115mm rocket, including photographs, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Tests and activities at Dover, Delaware, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Firing tests at Dover, Delaware, including photographs and data sheets, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Reports of tests at Dover, Delaware, 10/1944 --03/1945 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Dover, Delaware project, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - File W-81.09 - Air firings at Dover, Delaware, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Digests of air and ground operations at 4146th AAF Base Unit, Dover, Delaware, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - 15 Navy Ordnance pins, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Status of final reports, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - File W-210 - High velocity aircraft rocket tests, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Chamber calculations, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Handwritten notes
  - VICAR - wind tunnel tests and model (original data W-210 newton), undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - High velocity rocket (handwritten notes) [W-210 Boyd and Brewer (drawings)], 1944 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Rocket driver development, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Reports (with diagrams and photos) - "Two stage rocket grenade," "5/8 inch rocket," and "Cast Venturi spin rocket,", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Final report - "Series B, number 2.8: Flight Range Operations Supplement", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Corrections on reports, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Part I - "History of Section H, National Defense Research Committee" by Dr. C.N. Hickman (with photographs), 02/1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Part II - "History of Section H, National Defense Research Committee" by Dr. C.N. Hickman (with photographs), 02/1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - File W-19.1 - "Early work on jet-assisted take-offs," notes on report OSRD 5825, etc., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - W-112 rocket, 4.5inch T105 and T110 - test data and memos, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Report - "Heavy 4.5 inch rocket for aircraft and propellant charge for H4.5 inch rocket", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - W-111 rocket, 4.5 inch T38E5 data and memoranda, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Study of electronic gauge pressure measurements", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Alexander, Nelson E. - personnel file, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development - correspondence, memos, drawings, negatives, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence on contract termination, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Catalyst Research Corporation (subcontract no.1), 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Contract Manual (fiscal) and amendments, Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - HUMRRO (Human Resources Research Office) bibliography of reports 1959; Humrro special report 13 - "Fighter I: A Study of Effective and Ineffective Combat Performers," 1958, 1958 --1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hummro property, annual inventory, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hummro contract DA-44-188-ARO-2, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Contract NASr-171 (Dr. Shilling), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Navy Sub-Board of Inspection and Survey, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Part of missile housing, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints of lab, 02/1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Human Resources Research Organization (HUMRRO), 1954-1980; RG0038 Series 8; 1 Linear foot (Box 1)
  This series consists of materials from the Human Resources Research Organization (HUMRRO). These include publications, annual reports, bibliographies, and research reports. They are arranged alphabetically by subject files. The materials range in date from 1954-80, and were added to the University Archives collections from a backlog in 2003.
  - Annual Accomplishments Report, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography of Publications, 06/30/1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography of Publications, 06/30/1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biography of Publications, 06/30/1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography of Publications and Presentations, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bibliography of Publications and Presentations during FY 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - HumRRO-Research Memorandum-Methods and Devices for teaching data flow, 11/1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - HumRRO Reports, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - HumRRO-Professional Papers, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Interim Bibliography of Publications, 07/1966-12/31/1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interim Bibliography of Publications, 07/01/1967 --12/31/1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Library Accessions, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Preliminary Handbook on Procedures for Evaluating Mental Health, 08/1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Quarterly Progress Report, 04/1965 --06/1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Quarterly Research Reports, 03/1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Quarterly Research Reports, 06/1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Recent Library accessions, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Report of HumRRO Policy Council Meeting, 04/20/1965 --04/21/1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Report on Technical Advisory Services, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Research Memorandum, 01/1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Research Memorandum, 06/21/1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Derivation, Analysis, and Classification of Instructional Objectives, 05/1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Technical Report-Projected Manpower Needs and Projected Training Requirements, 06/1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Technical Report-Randomized Inquiry vs. Conventional Questionnaire Method, 06/1975 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "What HumRRO is Doing" (newsletter), 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Work Program for the Department of the Army, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Research records, 1946-1996; RG0038 Series 9; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2)
  This series contains reports, correspondence, handbooks, press releases, organization chart, memorandums, agreements, lease, bibliographies, photograph, newsletters, brochures, posters, proposal, and a Congressional Record. They range in date from 1946 to 1996. The material concern annual reports, strategies, sponsored research, the Office of Scientific Research and Development, ballistics, policies, procedures, the Human Resources Research Office (HumRRO), the Human Resources Research Organization (HumRRO), research, the Cooperative Education and Training Program, the Technical Education Center, separation of HumRRO from George Washington University, Raymond L. Bishplinghoff, patent policy, the Program of Policy Studies in Science and Technology, sourses of science and society, research support, grants, Innovation Information nd Analysis Project, nuclear energy, Innovation Information Center, obstacles to research, committee reports, the Interagency Panels on Early Childhood Research and Development, National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), Biological Sciences Communication Project, Center for Manpower Policy Studies, employment, staff, First Federal Congress Publications Project, Languages of the World Archive, Mid-Atlantic Regional Resource Center (MARRC), population research, National Endowment for the Humanities award for a humanities development program, and Eric Clearinghouse for Higher Education.
  - ERIC Clearinghouse for Higher Education, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grants to the University, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sponsored Research, 1976 --04/04/1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sponsored Research - Allegany Ballistics Laboratory (World War II), 04/12/1946 --05/24/1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sponsored Research--Handbook of Policies and Procedures, 1987, 09/1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sponsored Research - Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO), 1951-1969, 06/19/1956 --12/18/1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sponsored Research - Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO) - GW Settlement Agreement, 11/19/1969 --02/24/1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sponsored Research - Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO) Lease agreement, Alexandria, Virginia, 1969, 09/03/1969 --02/27/1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sponsored Research - Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO) Lists of publications, 1954-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sponsored Research - Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO) School of Engineering CETA program transfer to HUMRRO, 1981, 04/15/1980 --08/17/1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sponsored Research - Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO) Separation from GW, 1969-1970, 03/25/1969 --10/19/1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sponsored Research - Human Resources Research Office (HUMRRO) - Staff, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sponsored Research - Program of Policy Studies In Science And Technology, 01/1968 --03/25/1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sponsored Research - Program Of Policy Studies In Science And Technology Annual reports, 1966-1969, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sponsored Research - Program of Policy Studies In Science And Technology Graduate Programs, 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sponsored Research - Program of Policy Studies In Science And Technology - Lists of Publications, 1969-1975, 06/1969 --08/17/1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sponsored Research - Program of Policy Studies In Science And Technology Seven Year Review, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sponsored Research - Research Grants, 05/1985-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sponsored Research - Research Group, Social - Interagency Panels on Early Childhood and Adolescence Research and Development, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sponsored Research Research Projects - Biological Sciences Communication Project, 08/10/1965 --04/17/1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sponsored Research Research Projects - Center For Manpower Policy Studies, 03/1969 --10/1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sponsored Research Research Projects - Electronics Research Project--Staff --Bay, Zoltan (Chief Investigator) (1955), 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sponsored Research Research Projects - First Federal Congress Publications Project, 1965 --06/09/1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sponsored Research Research Projects - Languages Of The World Archives, 01/01/1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sponsored Research Research Projects - Mid-Atlantic Regional Resource Center, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sponsored Research Research Projects - Population Research Project, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photos of the Alleghany research project, 1944-1946; RG0038 Series 10; 2.5 Linear feet (Box 5, Box 4, Box 3, Box 2, Box 1)
  This series consists of photos of the Alleghany research project during World War II. The materials range in date from 1944-46. Subjects include individuals, groups, flamethrowers, bazookas, work shops, laboratory equipment, etc. (many photos are unidentified).